Hi and welcome back.
Jose: Ol e bem vindo de volta.
In this video we're looking at
Neste vdeo, estamos olhando
something a bit more complicated.
para algo um pouco mais complicado.
Understanding some slightly more complex HTML.
Entendendo um HTML um pouco mais complexo.
Let's create a new file in our project,
Vamos criar um novo arquivo em
which I'm gonna call middle_html.
nosso projeto, que eu vou chamar de middle_html.
By the way, the files in the project,
By the way, os arquivos no projeto, que
which are available at the start of this section,
esto disponveis no incio desta seo, tambm contm
also contain this exact code
esse cdigo exato e voc
and you can have a look at them.
pode dar uma olhada neles.
The files may be named slightly differently.
Os arquivos podem ser nomeados de forma ligeiramente diferente.
And that should be fine, I hope.
E isso deve estar bem, espero.
Once again, we're gonna do the same
Mais uma vez, vamos
from bs4_import BeautifulSoup
fazer o mesmo do bs4_import BeautifulSoup
and then I'm to paste in some HTML.
e depois eu vou colar algum HTML.
In this case, our HTML is going to represent
Nesse caso, nosso HTML representar um
an item that being on sale in an online website.
item que est sendo vendido em um site on-line.
So let's say we've managed to extract
Ento, digamos que conseguimos extrair
the content from the website.
o contedo do site.
We're gonna look at how to do that.
Ns vamos ver como fazer isso.
And we've ended up with this HTML here.
E acabamos com esse HTML aqui.
And with this HTML, we can find out the price of the item,
E com esse HTML, podemos descobrir o preo do item, a classificao por
the star-rating of the item and so forth.
estrelas do item e assim por diante.
Let me show you exactly what this looks like on the website.
Deixe-me mostrar exatamente o que isso parece no site.
Then it'll make a bit more sense.
Ento far um pouco mais de sentido.
What we've got here is a demo website
O que temos aqui  um site de
for web-scraping purposes.
demonstrao para fins de web scraping.
And let's say we've managed to extract
E digamos que conseguimos extrair
some HTML content from it.
algum contedo HTML dele.
The content that I've extracted and put in the file,
O contedo que eu extra e coloquei no
is the content that represents this object exactly.
arquivo  o contedo que representa exatamente esse objeto.
This bit of HTML here.
Este pedao de HTML aqui.
It could do as an image, a rating, a title,
Poderia fazer como uma imagem, uma classificao, um ttulo,
which seems to be partly missing and the price
que parece estar parcialmente ausente e o preo e, em seguida,
and then whether it's in stock or not,
se est em estoque ou no,
and, finally, a button to add it to the basket.
e, finalmente, um boto para adicion-lo  cesta.
So this HTML here is what we've copied into our file.
Ento este HTML aqui  o que copiamos em nosso arquivo.
And, again, we're going to learn how to get the HTML
E, novamente, vamos aprender como obter
from the site very soon.
o HTML do site muito em breve.
So let's go back into PyCharm and look at the HTML.
Ento vamos voltar para o PyCharm e olhar o HTML.
This is what we've got.
isso que temos.
We've got a list item here.
Ns temos um item da lista aqui.
That's because each element is actually in a list
Isso porque cada elemento est realmente em uma
in the website.
lista no site.
So, an element is a list item of a big list
Assim, um elemento  um item de lista de uma lista grande
that is formatted and structured in a bit of a different way
que  formatado e estruturado de um modo um pouco diferente
than you'd normally see lists.
do que voc normalmente veria nas listas.
Then, it's got an article inside it.
Ento, tem um artigo dentro dele.
You can see that the article spans, essentially,
Voc pode ver que o artigo abrange,
the entire document and that is
essencialmente, todo o documento e que
everything that we're interested in.
tudo em que estamos interessados.
We've got a div, whose has a class image container.
Temos um div, cujo continer de imagens de classe.
And a div in HTML is normally
E um div em
just something used to structure your content.
HTML normalmente  apenas algo usado para estruturar seu contedo.
So think of it as a rectangle
Ento pense nisso como um retngulo e
and you can put things inside it.
voc pode colocar coisas dentro dele.
And then here, what they've put, is a link and
E ento aqui, o que eles colocaram,  um
that's the a which is used for linking.
link e esse  o que  usado para vincular.
href is the url or the address of the page
href  o URL ou o endereo da
that the link goes to.
pgina que o link acessa.
And, inside the link, notice how the link starts here,
E, dentro do link, observe como o link comea aqui
and ends here in this closing tag.
e termina aqui nesta tag de fechamento.
You've got a image.
Voc tem uma imagem.
This is an image tag and this is the source of the image.
Esta  uma tag de imagem e esta  a fonte da imagem.
Some jpeg file.
Algum arquivo jpeg.
It's got some alt property and it's got a class property.
Tem alguma propriedade alt e tem uma propriedade de classe.
The alt property is the alternate text to show
A propriedade alt  o texto alternativo para mostrar se a
if the image cannot load for some reason.
imagem no pode ser carregada por algum motivo.
So that is the title of the book, actually.
Ento esse  o ttulo do livro, na verdade.
A Light in the Attic.
Uma luz no sto.
Outside the div we have a p tag, a paragraph tag,
Fora da div, temos uma tag p, uma tag de pargrafo, que  usada
which is used for the star-rating.
para a classificao por estrela.
This is a bit of a bizarre way of doing a star-rating,
Essa  uma maneira bizarra de fazer uma classificao
but you can see that there is a class star-rating
de estrelas, mas voc pode ver que h uma classificao de estrela de
and another class, which is separated by a space in HTML,
classe e outra classe, que  separada por um espao
called Three, with a capital T.
em HTML, chamado Trs, com uma letra maiscula.
So, this book has three stars.
Ento, este livro tem trs estrelas.
But you can inside it there are five i tags
Mas voc pode dentro dele, existem cinco tags i
which are used for icons.
que so usadas para cones.
So you can see that we must look at Three,
Ento voc pode ver que devemos olhar para
this class here, and not at the number of i tags
Three, esta classe aqui, e no para o nmero de tags i
because the i tags are always five.
porque as tags i so sempre cinco.
So we don't wanna look at that.
Ento no queremos olhar para isso.
We wanna look at this Three.
Ns queremos olhar para isto Trs.
Then outside the p you have an h3,
Ento fora do p voc tem um h3, que
which is the title of the book.
o ttulo do livro.
And you can see that the contents of the h3 are
E voc pode ver que o contedo do Presumivelmente, o nome do livro  muito longo e no
A Light in the ...
h3  A Light no. pode ser exibido totalmente no site.
Presumably, the book name is too long
No entanto, o h3 contm dentro dele, um
and it couldn't be displayed fully on the website.
link para a pgina do livro
However, the h3 contains inside it,
presumivelmente, e tambm tem uma propriedade de ttulo, um
a link to the book page presumably,
atributo de ttulo, que tambm  o ttulo do livro.
and also has a title property in it, a title attribute,
Ento voc tem um div que  o preo do produto.
that is also the title of the book.
E dentro dela, voc tem uma
Then you've got a div which is the product price.
tag p, que contm a classe, price_color, e
And inside it, you've got a p tag, which contains
que contm o preo do livro com um smbolo
the class, price_color,
de libra na frente dele.
and that contains the price of the book
Tambm dentro da div, voc tem essa outra tag p
with a pound symbol in front of it.
com a classe in_stock e outra classe chamada disponibilidade.
Also inside the div, you have this other p tag
Presumivelmente, essa classe in_stock s estar
with class in_stock and another class called availability.
presente no documento quando a coisa estiver em estoque.
Presumably this class in_stock will only be present
E se estiver fora de estoque,
in the document when the thing is in stock.
dir outra coisa, possivelmente.
And if it's out of stock,
Ns no sabemos disso.
it'll say something else, possibly.
Dentro dessa tag p, voc tem uma classe i que
We don't know that.
de cone, uma tag i, desculpe,
Inside that p tag you've got an i class
isso  para um cone e que tem um cone de classe ok.
which is from icon, an i tag, sorry, that's for an icon,
Ento voc gpt o texto em estoque.
and that has a class icon-ok.
Observe como isso  formatado de maneira estranha.
Then you've gpt the text In stock.
E, finalmente, voc tem um formulrio que contm um boto.
Notice how this is weirdly formatted.
Voc no precisa se preocupar muito com isso.
And, finally, you've got a form that has a button in it.
Ns no vamos estar olhando para isso.
You don't have to worry too much about that.
Ento voc fecha o div que voc comeou aqui.
We're not gonna be looking into this.
Finalmente voc fecha o artigo.
Then you close the div that you started up here.
Voc fecha o item da lista, que  para a coisa toda.
Finally you close the article.
E ento voc fecha seu HTML.
You close the list item, which is for the entire thing.
Ento, ns meio que entendemos esse cdigo.
And then you close your HTML.
Talvez no seja a coisa mais clara do mundo.
So, we sort of understand this code.
Mas vamos tentar extrair alguns dados dele.
Maybe it's not the clearest thing in the world.
Ento, vamos fazer exatamente isso.
But we are going to try to extract some data from it.
A primeira coisa , claro, criar nossa sopa.
So, let's do just that.
Ento, vamos fazer o
The first thing is, of course, to create our soup.
BeautifulSoup de ITEM_THML e o html. parser.
So we're gonna do BeautifulSoup of
Ento, vamos comear localizando o nome do item.
ITEM_THML, and the html.parser.
OK?
Then, we're going to start by locating the item name.
Assim, o nome do item, o ttulo do livro, , por exemplo, neste, voc lembra
Okay?
que temos
So the item name, the title of the book, is, for example,
uma imagem l que tem uma propriedade alt, que  o ttulo do livro.
in this a, you remember we've got an image there
Ou, mais normalmente, podemos tir-lo do ttulo real.
that has an alt property, which is the title of the book.
Este  um ttulo 3, como voc sabe.
Or, more normally, we can get it off the actual title.
E dentro dele h um a e o a tem ttulo de
This is a heading 3, as you know.
propriedade e esse  o ttulo do livro.
And inside it there's an a and the a has a property title
No podemos obter o contedo da propriedade
and that's the title of the book.
string porque ele
We cannot get the content out of the string property
tem trs pontos e falta parte do ttulo.
because that has a three dots
Ento temos que passar por aqui, ok?
and it's missing part of the title.
Vamos fazer isso.
So we must get it through here, okay?
Vamos criar uma funo, que ser o
Let's do that.
find_item_name.
Let's create a function, which is gonna be
Eu vou apresentar a voc uma nova
find_item_name.
maneira de localizar coisas que eu acho
I'm going to introduce to you a new way
que  substancialmente mais fcil do que a maneira padro.
of locating things which I think is
Ento, vamos identificar desde
substantially easier than the default way.
o incio do nosso documento, qual
So, we're going to identify from the start of our document,
caminho das crianas nos dar nosso elemento, nosso elemento.
what path of children will give us our element,
Ento, como voc pode ver, nossa tag de ttulo, nossa propriedade title aqui
our a element.
uma tag.
So as you can see, our title tag, our title property here
A tag a est na tag h3.
is in this a tag.
A tag h3 est na tag do artigo.
The a tag is in the h3 tag.
A tag de artigo est na tag
The h3 tag is in the article tag.
li, que est na tag body, que est na tag HTML.
The article tag is in the li tag,
Ento, vamos olhar para qualquer um desses pais.
which is in the body tag, which is in the HTML tag.
Ns podemos comear em qualquer lugar.
So, we're going to look at any of these parents.
Ns podemos comear no li.
We can start at anywhere.
Podemos comear no artigo.
We can start in the li.
Ns podemos comear no h3.
We can start at the article.
E ns vamos dizer, o artigo  o primeiro, por exemplo.
We can start at the h3.
Ento vem h3.
And we're gonna say, article is the first one, for example.
Ento vem um.
Then comes h3.
E voc pode ver isso porque essa div aqui, por exemplo, est
Then comes a.
no mesmo nvel dessa tag p.
And you can see that because this div here, for example,
O recuo no  muito bom, mas voc pode ver
is in the same level as this p tag.
que a tag div abre aqui e se fecha
The indentation is not very good,
aqui, o que significa que a
but you can see that the div tag opens here
tag p no est dentro dela.
and it closes here, which means
E a tag p fecha aqui, o que
the p tag is not inside it.
significa que a tag h3 no est dentro dela.
And the p tag closes here, which means
Ento, todos esto no mesmo nvel,
the h3 tag is not inside it.
o que significa que so todos filhos do artigo.
So these are all on the same level,
E o a  um filho de um h3.
which means they're all children of the article.
Ento, o que temos, essencialmente, no nosso localizador,  que
And the a is a children of an h3.
temos um artigo, depois separados
So, what we've got, essentially, in our locator,
por um espao, temos um h3 e temos um a.
is we've got an article, then separated by a space,
E esse tipo de hierarquia permite que o
we have a h3 and we have an a.
BeautifulSoup encontre elementos com muita facilidade, ok?
And this sort of hierarchy allows BeautifulSoup
Se voc quiser restringir-se a um artigo
to find elements very easily, okay?
especfico, por exemplo, se tiver muitos artigos, observe
If you wanted to narrow down into a specific article,
como esse artigo tem uma classe de product_pod.
for example, if you've had many articles,
Ento voc pode realmente dizer artigo. product_pod.
notice how this article has a class of product_pod.
E o que isso significa agora,  que voc est procurando o
So you can actually say article.product_pod.
artigo que tem classe product_pod,
And what this means now, is you're looking for the article
e dentro dele, voc est procurando por um
that has class product_pod, and inside it,
h3, e dentro dele voc est procurando por um a.
you're looking for an h3,
E isso, uma vez que
and inside it you're looking for an a.
voc faz, por exemplo, item_name  sopa. select_one (localizador) vai lhe dar
And this, once you do, for example,
tudo o que isso resulta.
item_name is soup.select_one(locator)
Essa coisa aqui  conhecida como
is going to give you whatever it is that this results in.
um localizador de CSS e  realmente poderosa.
This thing here is known as a CSS locator
Isso nos permite essencialmente fazer esse tipo de coisa.
and is really powerful.
E  assim que
It allows us to essentially do this sort of thing.
o CSS, a linguagem CSS, tambm localiza as coisas.
And it's the way that CSS, the CSS language,
Ns no vamos olhar para CSS neste curso, ou pelo menos
also locates things.
no ainda, mas,
We're not gonna look into CSS in this course,
e  assim que  chamado, essencialmente.
or at least not yet, but,
Em seus termos mais simples, podemos obter o
and that's what it's called, essentially.
pai, reduzi-lo por uma classe, se quisermos,
In its simplest terms, we can get the parent,
e depois descer para uma criana, e depois outra criana,
narrow it down by a class if we want
e assim por diante, at termos uma hierarquia que
and then go down to a child, and then another child,
no se repita em todo o site.
and so forth, until we have a hierarchy
Ento, se voc tem apenas um artigo com um
that is not repeated throughout the site.
product_pod, um h3 e um a, ento isso
So if you only have one article with a product_pod,
lhe dar essa hierarquia que voc pode procurar.
one h3 and one a, then that's gonna give you
Agora que voc tem o, no
this hierarchy here that you can search for.
vamos cham-lo de item_name, vamos
Now that you've got the,
cham-lo de item_link.
we're not gonna call it item_name,
Agora que voc tem o
we're gonna call it item_link.
item_link, podemos dizer item_name = item_link. attrs ['title'].
Now that you've got the item_link,
Novamente, isso acessa os atributos do link.
we can say item_name = item_link.attrs['title'].
Nosso link est aqui.
Again, this accesses the attributes of the link.
E ns vamos acessar a propriedade title ou
Our link is here.
atributo desse link.
And we're gonna access the title property
E ento podemos imprimir o nome do item.
or attribute of that link.
Vamos executar a funo.
And then we can print the item name out.
E, lembre-se de executar o arquivo middle_html e, voc pode ver que obtemos
Let's run the function.
um A Light in the Attic impresso.
And, remember to run you middle_html file, and,
Agora, usando esses localizadores, voc pode
you can see that we get A Light in the Attic printed out.
localizar essencialmente qualquer coisa.
Now using these locators,
Ento, aqui est um pequeno desafio para voc.
you can essentially locate anything.
Usando um localizador, voc vai realmente usar o mesmo.
So here's a small challenge for you.
Descubra o link para esta pgina de itens.
Using a locator, you're gonna actually use the same one.
Ento, o que voc est procurando  esta href aqui.
Find out the link to this items page.
Tenho certeza que voc pode fazer isso.
So what you're looking for is this href here.
Eu espero que voc tenha conseguido.
I'm sure you can do it.
Tudo o que temos que
I hope you managed.
fazer , essencialmente, acessar
All that we have to do is, essentially, access the same
o mesmo localizador, mas em vez do ttulo, acessar outro atributo, que  o atributo href.
locator, but instead of the title,
Ento, vamos copiar, colar aqui e
access another attribute, which is the href attribute.
vamos chamar de find_item_link, e ento vamos
So we're going to copy,
acessar o
paste it in here and we're gonna call it
atributo href aqui.
find_item_link, and then we're going to access the
Novamente,  o mesmo elemento, artigo com
href attribute here.
a classe product_pod.
Again, it's the same element,
A tag h3 que  uma criana.
article with product_pod class.
A tag que  filha disso.
The h3 tag which is a child.
E ento ns vamos selecionar isso e,
The a tag which is a child of that.
finalmente, vamos acessar o atributo disso,
And then we're gonna select that
e ns vamos imprimi-lo.
and, finally, we're gonna access the attribute of that,
Mas, claro, agora que temos esse item_link que
and we're gonna print it out.
um bom nome para
But, of course, now that we have this item_link
nosso link, vamos fazer isso.
that's a pretty good name for our link,
Ento, acesse o item, desculpe,
we're gonna just do this.
a tag e acesse a propriedade href.
So access the item, sorry, the tag,
E ento podemos trazer isso para fora.
and then access the href property of that.
Ooh, vamos deletar isso.
And then we can bring that out.
E corra de novo.
Ooh, let's delete this.
E agora voc pode ver que recebemos o ttulo e, em
And run again.
seguida, obtemos o link aqui tambm.
And now you can see that we get the title
Este  um link relativo, por isso no lhe d
and then we get the link here as well.
o nome de domnio inteiro e o site e tudo mais.
This is a relative link, so it doesn't give you the
Tudo bem.
entire domain name and the website and everything.
Aprenderemos a lidar com isso mais tarde.
That's okay.
OK?
We'll learn how to deal with that later on.
Usando este localizador agora podemos encontrar outras coisas.
Okay?
Assim, podemos encontrar, por
Using this locator now we can find other things.
exemplo, o preo do item e a classificao do item.
So, we can find, for example, the item price
No  to fcil, porque voc vai
and the item rating.
ter que fazer alguns outros clculos.
It's not so easy to do because you're gonna have to do
Por exemplo, se voc quiser encontrar o
some other calculations.
preo do item,
For example, if you wanted to find the item's price,
que est aqui, voc ver o artigo.
which is here,
Ento voc potencialmente olha para
you're gonna look at article.
um p que tem classe price_color.
Then you're potentially look at a p
E ento voc vai olhar
that has price_color class.
para o seu contedo, o contedo da string dele.
And then you're gonna look at its contents,
Mas isso no  um nmero,  uma string.
the string contents of it.
Ento voc pode querer retirar o
But this is not a number, it is a string.
sinal de libra e usar uma expresso regular para extrair este grupo.
So you may want to strip out the pound sign
Acho que isso seria um timo
and use a regular expression to extract this group.
exerccio para revisarmos o que aprendemos na
I think this would be a great exercise
ltima seo e tentar.
for us to review what we've learned in the last section
Tente extrair 51. 77 como float usando BeautifulSoup e
and give it a go.
expresses regulares.
Try to extract 51.77 as a float using BeautifulSoup
D uma chance.
and regular expressions.
Pause o vdeo e v em frente.
Give that a go.
Eu espero que voc tenha conseguido.
Pause the video and go for it.
uma maneira mais complicada de fazer as coisas.
I hope you managed.
Mas o que vamos fazer , em primeiro lugar, localizar isso.
It's a bit of a more-complicated way to go about things.
Primeiro de tudo, pegue essa string com o BeautifulSoup.
But what we're going to do is, first of all, locate this.
Ento, vou criar uma nova funo, find_item_price.
First of all, get this string out with BeautifulSoup.
E ento eu vou
So I'm going to create a new function, find_item_price.
definir meu localizador, que ser artigo. product_pod e dentro dele
And then I'm going to define my locator,
temos p. price_color.
which is gonna be article.product_pod
Ento aqui estamos acessando o artigo que tem essa
and inside it we've got p.price_color.
classe e o p que tem essa classe.
So here we're accessing the article that has this class
E isso vai nos dar uma boa compreenso,
and the p that has this class.
ou vai dar uma boa
And that's gonna give us a pretty good understanding, or,
compreenso ao BeautifulSoup sobre como chegar l.
it's gonna give BeautifulSoup a good understanding
Ento, vamos acessar o
of how to get there.
item_price que ser sopa. selecione. um (localizador). corda.
Then, we're going to access the item_price
Tudo o que est acontecendo aqui  encontrar essa tag
which is going to be soup.select.one(locator).string.
e estamos acessando o contedo dela.
All that's happening here is we're finding that tag
Ento isso vai nos dar um sinal de libra 51. 77 ou por mais
and we're accessing the string content of it.
que fosse.
So this is gonna give us pound sign 51.77
Sim, 51 77, ento isso nos deu isso.
or however much it was.
Agora, temos isso, temos que
Yeah, 51.77, so this has given us that.
usar nossa expresso regular para extra-la.
Now, we have this, we have to use our regular expression
Ento, indo para o topo do arquivo, eu vou
in order to extract it.
importar o mdulo re, importar re.
So, going to the top of the file,
Observe como estou fazendo essa importao no topo do arquivo.
I'm gonna import the re module, import re.
E de blah blah blah, importe
Notice how I am doing this import re at the top of the file.
alguma coisa diretamente abaixo dela.
And from blah blah blah, import something else
Essa  uma conveno de classificao Python para fazer
directly underneath it.
esse tipo de
This is Python sort-of convention to do
importao no topo, esse tipo de importao logo abaixo delas.
these type of imports at the top,
Agora que temos o re
this type of imports just directly below them.
mdulo, podemos definir nosso padro, a
Now that we've got the re module,
expresso regular que estamos procurando.
we can define our pattern,
E este vai ser,
the regular expression we're looking for.
em primeiro lugar, o smbolo da libra 51. 77
And this is going to be, first of all,
Isso vai combinar.
the pound symbol 51.77.
Queremos extrair 51. 77 como um nmero.
This is going to match.
Ento vamos coloc-lo dentro desses
We want to extract 51.77 as a number.
colchetes para que possamos extra-lo usando o grupo.
So we're gonna put it inside these brackets
Ento, claro, no estamos interessados nisso 51. 77 apenas, mas se o
so that we can extract it using the group.
preo fosse mudar, ns gostaramos de
Then, of course, we're not interested in this 51.77 only,
obter o preo alterado.
but if the price were to change,
Ento, ao invs de colocar 51 77 aqui, vamos ter que
we'd wanna get the changed price.
usar algo que nos permita obter
So instead of putting 51.77 in here,
um intervalo de nmeros.
we're gonna have to use something that will allow us
E a maneira como vamos fazer isso
to get a range of numbers.
fazendo de zero a nove dentro dos colchetes.
And the way we're gonna do that is by doing
Este  um intervalo de nmeros de zero a nove.
zero to nine inside the square brackets.
Ento vamos fazer mais, ento isso
This is a range of numbers from zero to nine.
vai nos dar um ou mais desses nmeros.
Then we're gonna do plus, so that's gonna give us
E ento, vamos nos certificar de colocar uma
one or more of these numbers.
barra invertida na frente do
And then, we're going to make sure to put a backslash
ponto para que ele corresponda ao ponto e no a qualquer coisa,
in front of the dot so that it matches
que  o que significa em expresses regulares.
the dot and not anything, which is what it means
E para o 77, vamos fazer o mesmo.
in regular expressions.
Zero a nove mais.
And for the 77, we're going to do the same.
Ento, vamos procurar e obter nossos grupos.
Zero to nine plus.
Ento nossos grupos, ou
Then we're going to search and get our groups.
nosso matcher vai ser re. pesquisa (padro e item_price).
So our groups, or our matcher is going to be
E, novamente, isso nos dar dois grupos.
re.search(pattern, and item_price).
Grupo
And, again, this is going to give us two groups.
zero, que ser a coisa toda correspondente.
Group zero, which is going to be the entire
E ento matcher. group (1), que ser o primeiro grupo
thing that matches.
entre os colchetes.
And then matcher.group(1), which is going to be
Ento, isso vai ser 51. 77 sem o smbolo da libra.
the first group that is between the brackets.
Ok, isso vai ser 51. 77
So that's gonna be 51.77 without the pound symbol.
Isso vai ser 51. 77 sem o smbolo.
Okay, this is gonna be 51.77.
Ento, podemos, de fato, transform-lo em um float.
This is gonna be 51.77 without the symbol.
Ok, estamos imprimindo o float desse matcher.
So we can, indeed, turn it into a float.
E ento vamos rodar isso e ver o que acontece.
Okay, we're printing out the float of this matcher.
E, como voc pode ver, temos 51. 77 com o sinal de
And, so let's run that and see what happens.
libra, e 51. 77 sem o sinal de libra.
And, as you can see, we get 51.77 with the pound sign,
Digamos que quisssemos imprimir, mas com
and 51.77 without the pound sign.
um desconto de 20%.
Let's say we wanted to print it out but
Ns podemos multiplicar por 0. 8 e isso deve funcionar porque
at a 20% discount.
um nmero agora, no  uma string.
We can multiply by 0.8 and this should work
E, como voc pode ver, funciona.
because it's a number now, it's not a string.
Ns temos 41. 416.
And, as you can see, it works.
Ento isso  muito legal.
We get 41.416.
Agora aprendemos como extrair um
So that's pretty awesome.
nmero usando o BeautifulSoup e expresses regulares de um site.
We have now learned how to extract a number
Assim, por exemplo, as coisas que podemos fazer agora, uma
using BeautifulSoup and regular expressions from a website.
vez que aprendemos,  claro, como interagir com o site, o que faremos em
So, for example, the things that we can do now,
breve, nesta seo, voc pode, por exemplo,
once we learn, of course, how to interact with the website,
acompanhar os preos dos itens online.
which we will do shortly, in this section,
Por exemplo, digamos que voc jogue badminton e
you can, for example, track item prices online.
queira acompanhar o preo das raquetes de badminton ao longo
For example, let's say you play badminton
do tempo para descobrir quando voc deve comprar uma.
and you wanna track the price of badminton rackets
Voc poderia fazer isso com um aplicativo Python
over time in order to find out when you should buy one.
simples, que basicamente faz o download do site
You could do this with a simple Python app
e examina-o usando algo parecido com isso.
that essentially downloads the site
Finalmente, vamos descobrir a classificao do item.
and looks through it using something like this.
A classificao vai ser um pouco mais
Finally, let's find out the item's rating.
complicada, porque temos que olhar exatamente
The rating is gonna be a bit more complicated
um atributo, que  este trs aqui.
because we have to look at exactly one attribute,
Mas, claro, isso est em uma tag p e h
which is this Three here.
muitas tags p por a.
But, of course, this is in a p tag
Ento, vamos descobrir isso.
and there are many p tags around.
Vamos descer aqui.
So, let's find this out.
Ns vamos fazer def_find_item_rating.
Let's go down here.
O localizador vai ser artigo. product_pod,
We're gonna do def_find_item_rating.
product_pod e dentro
The locator is going to be article.product_pod,
dele, p. classificao por estrelas.
product_pod,
Isso porque o pargrafo que estamos procurando  o
and inside it, p.star-rating.
que tem essa classificao de estrelas da classe.
That is because the paragraph we're looking for
Em CSS, as classes so sempre separadas por espaos.
is the one that has this class star-rating.
Ento, o que essa tag p tem so duas classes.
In CSS, classes are always separated by spaces.
Classificao por estrelas e trs.
So what this p tag has is two classes.
Ento, estamos procurando o pargrafo que tem
Star-rating and Three.
a classe de classificao por estrelas e tambm
So we're looking for the paragraph
tem outras classes.
that has the star-rating class
Mas no estamos limitados a apenas este.
and it also has other classes.
Ento este localizador encontrar esse pargrafo.
But we're not limited to only this one.
Tem um p. classificao por estrelas.
So this locator will find that paragraph.
E se quisssemos tambm encontr-lo com a classe Trs,
It has a p.star-rating.
poderamos fazer isso.
And if we wanted to also found it with the Three class,
Mas no queremos encontr-lo com duas classes, apenas
we could do this.
no caso de a classificao mudar.
But we don't want to find it with two classes,
Ento, vamos ficar com isso apenas.
just in case the rating changes.
O elemento de classificao de estrelas, a tag
So, we're gonna stick it with this only.
ou a tag de classificao de estrelas ser sopa. select_one (localizador).
The star-rating element, the tag, or the star-rating tag
Ento isso nos d a etiqueta, ok?
is going to be soup.select_one(locator).
Agora, podemos tirar as tags de classe disso.
So this gives us the tag, okay?
Ento as classes so star-rating_tag. attrs ('classe').
Now, we can get the class tags out of it.
E agora, quando a BeautifulSoup extrai, sero
So the classes are star-rating_tag.attrs('class').
duas classes, essas duas.
And this is now when BeautifulSoup extracts it
Isso  o que vai nos dar.
it's going to be two classes, these two.
Ento precisamos descobrir o que  isso.
This is what it's gonna give us.
Mas, lembre-se, pode ser o primeiro.
So we need to find out what this is.
No necessariamente tem que ser a
But, remember, it could be the first one.
segunda classe, ento essa lista poderia ser assim.
It doesn't necessarily have to be the second class,
No podemos simplesmente selecionar o segundo elemento.
so this list could be like this.
Isso seria muito fcil.
We cannot just select the second element.
Ento, o que vamos fazer  recriar essa lista
That would be too easy.
de classes, mas sem
So what we're going to do, is
essa classificao de estrela.
we're going to recreate this classes list,
Tenho certeza que voc pode fazer isso usando uma
but without this star-rating.
compreenso de lista ou a funo de filtro.
I'm sure you can do that using either a list comprehension
D uma chance.
or the filter function.
Tenho certeza que voc conseguiu.
Give it a go.
Existem duas maneiras de fazer isso.
I'm sure you managed.
Poderamos dizer que rating_classes  r para r
There are two ways that we could do this.
em classes, se r no for igual a 'star-rating'.
We could say rating_classes is r for r in classes
Este seria um caminho.
if r is not equal to 'star-rating'.
Ou poderamos fazer o rating_classes igual ao filtro de lambda x para x no  uma classificao
This would be one way.
de estrelas nas classes.
Or we could do rating_classes equals filter
Ok, qualquer um desses seria perfeitamente adequado.
of lambda x for x is not star-rating in classes.
Os cdigos que voc ver online tm isso.
Okay, either of these would be perfectly suitable.
Ento, vamos deixar a compreenso da lista no vdeo.
The codes that you'll see online has this.
Se voc quer olhar para o outro modo de fazer as
So we're gonna leave the list comprehension in the video.
coisas, confira o vdeo que est vinculado no incio da
If you wanna look out at the other way of doing things
palestra e tambm, no incio da seo, e tambm
check out the video
na palestra.
which is linked at the start of the lecture and also,
Agora esta lista aqui deve conter um nico elemento.
at the start of the section, and also in the lecture.
Este trs.
Now this list here should contain a single element.
Ento, podemos apenas dizer print (rating_classes) [0].
This Three.
Estamos assumindo
So, we can just say print(rating_classes)[0].
que o pargrafo no ter outras tags, por exemplo, hello class.
We're assuming that the paragraph is not going to have
Isso seria estranho.
any other tags, say, for example, hello class.
Mas, voc sabe, isso pode acontecer.
It would be weird.
E esse mtodo, se for o caso, no  ideal para isso.
But, you know, it can happen.
Mas, olhando para
And this method, if that's the case, is not ideal for that.
alguns dos itens no site, parece que eles so apenas duas classes.
But, through looking at a few of the items on the website,
Classificao por estrelas e a classificao.
it seems that they're only ever two classes.
Ento, isso poderia ser quatro, cinco ou trs e assim por diante.
Star-rating and the rating.
Finalmente, vamos chamar isso de find_item_rating e
So that could be Four, or Five, or Three and so on.
rodar isso e voc tem aqui.
Finally, let's call this one find_item_rating
Ns temos o nmero de estrelas neste livro.
and run this and there you have it down here.
Assim, poderamos usar isso agora para pesquisar os livros e
We've got the number of stars in this book.
poderamos, por exemplo, baixar a pgina
So we could use this now to search the books
inteira e descobrir quais livros tm
and we could, for example, download the entire page
cinco estrelas e esto abaixo de 20 libras.
and find which books have five stars
E isso seria algo que poderamos fazer.
and are under 20 pounds.
Mas antes de fazermos isso,  claro, temos
And that would be something that we could do.
que aprender a extrair o contedo do site fazendo
But before we do that, of course,
o download do site.
we have to learn to extract the content from the site
Ento vamos fazer isso muito em breve.
by downloading the website.
Mas primeiro eu quero te contar um
So we're going to do that very soon.
pouco sobre como melhorar essa estrutura.
But first I just want to tell you a little bit
Voc nem sempre vai, ou no
about how to improve on this structure.
vai querer ter essas funes de nvel superior para cada coisa
You're not always going to,
que est encontrando.
or you're not gonna want to have these top-level functions
Voc no vai querer que suas funes sejam
for each thing you're finding.
impressas, necessariamente.
You're not gonna want your functions
Ento, vamos tornar as coisas um pouco melhores.
to be printing things out, necessarily.
Vamos comear a separar as coisas
So we're gonna make things a bit better.
em classes e coisas assim, para
We're going to start separating things into classes
que voc tenha uma idia melhor de como eu recomendaria
and things like that
que voc analisasse
just so you have a better idea
o HTML e lidasse com
of how I'd recommend that you go about
isso de maneira agradvel em seus programas.
parsing the HTML and sort of
Ento, com isso dito, at o prximo vdeo.